The one name they all fear.
Van Helsing is a horror, adventure, action film directed by Stephen Sommers.
Famed monster slayer Gabriel Van Helsing is dispatched to Transylvania to assist
the last of the Valerious bloodline in defeating Count Dracula.
Anna Valerious reveals that Dracula has formed an unholy alliance with Dr.
Frankenstein's monster and is hell-bent on exacting a
centuries-old curse on her family.
Van Helsing, played by Hugh Jackman.
Anna Valerious, played by Kate Beckinsale.
Count Vladislaus Dracula, played by Richard Roxburgh.
Carl, played by David Wenham.
Frankenstein's Monster, played by Shuler Hensley.
Aleera, played by Elena Anaya.
Van Helsing is a 2004 action horror film written
and directed by Stephen Sommers.
It stars Hugh Jackman as monster hunter Van Helsing
and Kate Beckinsale as Anna Valerious.
Van Helsing is an homage to the Universal Horror Monster films from the 1930s and 1940s (also produced by Universal Pictures
which were in turn partially based on novels by Bram Stoker and Mary Shelley), of which Sommers is a fan.
The eponymous character was inspired by the Dutch vampire hunter Abraham
Van Helsing from Irish author Bram Stoker's novel Dracula.
Distributed by Universal Pictures, the film includes a number of monsters such as
Count Dracula (and other vampires), Frankenstein's monster, Duergar, Mr.
Hyde and werewolves in a way similar to the multi-monster movies that Universal produced in the 1940s,
such as Frankenstein Meets the Wolf Man, House of Frankenstein and House of Dracula.
The film grossed $300.2 million worldwide against a budget of
$160–170 million but was not well received by critics.
The film explores themes of transylvania, vampire,
vatican (holy see), bite, castle.
The tone is dark.